Today it's a different day altogether for all of you,
今天 對於你們所有人來說 都是一個完全不同的日子
because this is the Puja of Adi Shakti.
因為今天是太初母性力量崇拜的日子
And Adi Shakti is a complete personality,
太初之母擁有完整的特質
it's not only the left side that you know.
不僅是你們所知道的左脈的特質
You all know only the left side, from Shri Ganesha
你們都只知道左脈從錫呂 格涅沙開始
I didn't want to tell you about the right side to begin with,
我並不想一開始就和你們談論右脈
because those who have gone through the right side got just lost.
因為那些穿越右脈的人全都迷失了
They got Gayatri Mantra from the writings
他們從一些書籍中獲得了Gayatri口訣
but they didn't know what it was about,
卻並不知道這是什麼
they just used to learn it by heart.
他們只是習慣於熟記
They didn't also know the real meaning of it,
卻並不瞭解它的真正含義
and that is how they moved on the right side
這就是他們如何走向了右脈
and, I don’t know, they landed up at the Agnya;
我不知道怎麼說 他們最終停留在額輪
and then they were trying for the Self-realization.
然後他們試圖獲得自覺
They were promised that if you do this right side properly,
他們曾得到承諾 如果你們恰當的使用右脈
you will reach to the ultimate goal of Self-realization.
會達到終極目標即自覺
But none of them reached there.
但他們中間沒有一人達成
Most of them got into a terrible temper,
他們大部分人脾氣暴躁
terrible temper of cursing others, of destroying others.
詛咒別人 摧毀他人 很壞的脾氣
All these things they learnt through their right-side movement.
所有這些他們都是 通過右脈的行動而習得的
There was no kundalini awakening,
靈量並未喚醒
and they were made to go up to the, at the most, Agnya Chakra,
他們最終 至多只達到了額輪
and then they collapsed into different places of complete ignorance.
然後跌落到各種完全無明的狀態
All these books were written without understanding
所有這些書籍的撰寫者都不瞭解
that it's not easy to go via right side,
通過右脈來升進並不容易
but best was to awaken your kundalini.
最好是喚醒你的昆達利尼
The kundalini directly takes you up in the center of all the chakras,
昆達利尼直接在中脈 帶你穿過所有的輪穴
up to the Agnya and crosses Agnya, and goes beyond Agnya
直到額輪 並穿過額輪 超越額輪
into the Sahasrara, and then it pierces through the Sahasrara.
達到頂輪 然後突破頂輪
Now, what is so important about the Brahmarandra, from where it pierces?
那麼 梵穴到底有什麼重要性 它是從哪裡穿越的呢
I never told you about it.
之前我從沒和你們談過這些
But now I think for most of you the time has come.
但是現在 我想對你們大部分人來說 是時候了
You see in the childhood the child has a talu,
你看 在童年時期 孩童有一個talu
is the fontanel bone area which is pulsating always.
即鹵門骨區域 那裡不停地跳動
It is pulsating because the spirit entered through that area,
那裡會跳動是因為靈進入了這個區域
and when you close it, it settles in the heart.
當鹵門閉合後 靈便安頓在心臟中
Now you have to become the spirit-oriented person,
現在你必須成為靈性導向的人
but how to enter into the Sahasrara was the problem.
但是 如何進入頂輪 這是個問題
The tantrikas who were there, they went through the right, left side,
之前的譚崔教徒 他們穿越了左脈
and they developed all the practices of black – we should say, the left side.
我們應該說 他們發展出所有左脈的黑巫術
So the right-sided became extremely hot-tempered, I should say,
因此 偏右脈的人變得極度暴躁 極度暴躁
extremely ambitious, ferocious,
極具野心殘忍可怕
and they started killing people on the basis of cursing.
他們用詛咒來殺人
They are very good at cursing people;
他們擅長詛咒人
to be always forward, push back all the people,
總是不斷沖向前 把所有人都推到後面
and override everybody's rights.
踐踏每個人的權利
They were regarded as the most ambitious and most powerful people.
他們被視為最野心勃勃 和最有權勢的人
Now the brahmins and to some extent the kshatriyas,
現在 婆羅門 在某種程度上還有刹帝利
they then took the right side.
他們開始走向右脈
Because of the right side they became very powerful, no doubt.
因為在右脈 毫無疑問 他們開始變得很有權勢
They got all the powers over the world
他們擁有全世界所有的權力
and they were regarded as extremely powerful and majestic people,
他們被視為非常強大和尊貴的人
but they were not, because they were so hot-tempered.
但他們並非如此 因為他們是如此暴躁易怒
Hot-tempered people cannot be spiritual.
易怒的人不可能有靈性
So they were told, “You'll get your spirituality, don't worry, keep moving,”
有人告訴他們 你會得到 你的靈性 別擔心 繼續前進
and the seven chakras were described, on the right side.
他們描述了右脈上的七個輪穴
According to them there is bhuh, bhurvah.
據他們所寫 有Bhuh和Bhurvah
Bhuh is this prithivi, is this world, bhuh.
Bhuh是大地母親（prithivi） 也就是這個世界
Bhurvah is the complete cosmos, or we can call it antariksha.
Bhurvah是整個宇宙 或者我們可以稱之為虛空（Antariksha）
Swaha: swaha is consumption at the Nabhi Chakra;
Swaha是指臍輪的消化功能
and swadha is the, swadha is the consumption inside,
Swadha是內部的消化
is to absorption – swaha, swadha.
即吸收swaha swadha
Then is the mind, heart – manah.
然後是心智 心 manah
After manah came the Agnya – the Vishuddhi.
在Manaha之後是額輪 喉輪
The Vishuddhi is janah, collectivity, people,
喉輪是Janah 集體 人群
go to the people – janah.
走向人群 Janah
Then at the Agnya it is tapah.
然後是額輪Tapah
In tapah we have Christ in the center;
在Tapaha的位置 中央是基督
left side they had Jainism, right side Christianity.
左邊是耆那教 右邊是基督教
They were not actually ascending path,
事實上這些並非升進的道路
they were just side outlets, we can say,
對於求道者的能量來說 那只是旁邊的岔路
Now this happened for ages in India.
這種情況在印度由來已久 直到現在
All the gurus, all the sadhus,
所有的導師 所有苦行僧
all the big tapassvis, all of them did this.
所有大苦行者 所有這些人都這麼做
But where did they reach?
但他們達到了什麼境界呢
Tapassvis were the people who could give curses –
苦行者是指那些會發出尖刻詛咒的人
With the kataksha, is with the glance of the eye they could kill somebody,
只要看一眼 他們就能殺人
they could burn something; all right-sided powers they had.
就能燒毀東西 他們擁有所有右脈的力量
And with these right-sided powers, where did they reach?
那麼 這些右脈的力量 使他們達到了什麼境界呢
To hell, I should say, in a way – if not, in the limbo, as you call it.
去了地獄 我要說 在某種程度上 如果不是去了地獄 就是在地獄邊緣
There nobody got Self-realization.
在那裡 沒有人得到自覺
You read the old books from India, but even otherwise the Greeks;
你閱讀印度古書（就會知道）
and all kinds of aggressive people, Germans
以及各種各樣好鬥的人 德國人
– all of them were aggressive – Catholics, and also you had Romans.
所有這些人都那麼富有侵略性 天主教徒 還有羅馬人
All of them were aggressive,
所有這些人都愛好侵略
and were taking the land and property of other countries;
他們掠奪其他國家的土地和財產
extremely aggressive, they believed in the killing of the people -
極其好鬥 他們信仰殺人
extremely, insulting, hot-tempered people.
極為傲慢無禮 性格暴躁
So how to bring them to the normal, to the central path?
那麼 如何使他們恢復正常 來到中正的道路
One side was, as I told you, bhuh, bhurv, swaha, swadha,
一方面 正如我所說 bhuh bhurva swaha swadha
it’s consumption – this was done by Guru Principle.
這是消化清除 通過導師原理運作
Then we have manah, janah – that is collective.
後我們有manah janah 這是集體性
They became collective, no doubt, because they were so powerful
由此 他們變得合群 毫無疑問 因為他們如此強有力
that they had such a lot of people with them to fight for the oppressive.
因此有許多人 跟隨他們一起來對抗侵略
With their oppressive temperament they were fighting on people
而曾經他們卻因這種侵略人的性格 打壓人民
and were oppressing them.
壓迫人民
All this kind of … generation came in the history,
如你們所知 這種類型的一代代 曾在歷史上出現過的人
Wars were created, then so many people were killed.
他們引發戰爭 殺害那麼多人
We had Hitler as the maximum of cruelty.
像希特勒 就是極度殘忍的例子
They never cared for humanity.
他們從不關心人類
Then ultimately it came to the Agnya.
最終他們走向了額輪
Agnya also they killed Jesus Christ, they destroyed Jesus Christ.
那些人還殺害了額輪的神祇 耶穌基督 他們殺死了耶穌基督
They destroyed so many great saints who were really saints
他們毀滅了許多走在 中正道路上的真正聖人
All this happened since the time of Rama, all that has happened.
所有這些都從羅摩時代開始發生 發生了這麼多事
And one after another so many rakshasas came,
如此多的羅刹魔相繼出世
and they destroyed the peaceful culture of the world;
他們破壞了全世界的和平文化
extremely arrogant show-offs, as we can call them,
極度自負炫耀
very aggressive people.
我們可以稱他們是極富侵略性的人
And this aggression came, came with such a great force,
這種侵略伴隨著巨大的暴力而來
and followed one after another.
一個接一個
It went up to a point.
達到一個極點
When people reacted, they were killed and were destroyed.
如果有人作出回應 便被殺害和毀壞
So horrible people were created;
降生了如此可怕的人
all these people, as they were aggressive and destructive.
所有這些人是那樣的 性好侵略和具有破壞性
This nature is still within us, some people, because they are right-sided.
這種本性仍存在於我們 某些人的體內 因為他們傾向右脈
All right-side people had this problem: temper, aggression, controlling others.
所有右脈的人都有這個問題 壞脾氣 好侵略 宰製人
The growth stopped, and there was no spiritual growth.
他們的發展停止了 沒有任何靈性上的成長
They wanted to have spirituality,
他們想要擁有靈性
but with this kind of behavior they had developed, spirituality ran away.
但由於發展出了這樣的行為 使他們喪失了靈性
We had so many incarnations.
我們有過如此多的降世神祇
They all were killed, crucified, or were finished.
他們都被殺害 釘在十字架上或者被毀掉
There was no possibility of saving human beings in general.
總而言之 沒有機會拯救人類
One bad man came and he ruined the whole world.
一個壞人來到世上 他毀掉了全世界
We had one Hitler who really hit all the people,
世上有過一個希特勒 他真地打擊了所有人
all the countries, all the nations, and we were all finished.
所有國家 所有民族 我們全都完蛋
All this is because we have taken to right-sided movement
所有這些都是因為我們走向了右脈
which they thought was easier for spirituality, which was not.
我們認為在這邊發展靈性更容易 其實不是
So they crossed all the limits, and they reached a stage
因此他們跨越了界限 達到了另一個階段
that they became absolutely devils, rakshasas,
完全變成惡魔 羅刹魔
without realizing that human beings are rakshasas,
他們沒有意識到人類變成了羅刹魔
that's what they become.
他們變成了這個樣子
Even their gurus were like that,
甚至連他們的導師也象那樣
and nothing but they tortured even the incarnations,
毫無建樹 只會折磨人 甚至折磨降世神祇
all the incarnations were tortured by them.
所有降世神祇都被他們折磨過
It was really – how they saved themselves is remarkable,
他們自救的努力確實非凡
but ultimately they couldn't produce any results.
但最終沒有結果
So the first thing I tried was to study about the kundalini,
所以 我所嘗試的第一件事 就是研究昆達利尼
that I should be able to raise the kundalini.
我應該是能夠提升起昆達利尼的
And I knew I had come for that,
我早就知道自己是為此而來
not for anything else, but only to raise the kundalini of people
不為其它任何事 只是為了 提升人類的昆達利尼
so that they take to the central path, not to the right or to the left.
以使他們能夠走向中脈 而不會偏右或偏左
But I told you the knowledge of the left side, plus raising your kundalini.
但我之前告訴了你們關於左脈 的知識並提升了你們的昆達利尼
By raising your kundalini you broke your Sahasrara,
通過昆達利尼的升起 你們突破了頂輪
and you entered into the realm of real joy, of reality.
由此進入了實相的喜樂之境
All these bad qualities started falling out.
所有那些不好的特質開始脫落
In the central path first the Mooladhara came.
中脈的第一個輪穴是根輪
By the awakening of the Mooladhara and the central path,
通過喚醒根輪和中脈 你們變成純潔的人
Your eyes became pure, your licentiousness went away,
你們的雙眼變得純潔 你們脫離了放縱和低俗
Unless and until that happens you cannot be in Sahaja Yoga.
除非如此 否則你們仍不算 進入了霎哈嘉瑜伽
You cannot be a licentious, you cannot be a flirtish,
你們不能放縱 不可以輕浮
you cannot be a man who wants to grab money from others and all that,
你們不應該是那種 想從別人手上 賺取金錢的人以及所有那些
or anyone who is very aggressive could be in Sahaja Yoga.
或者說任何極富侵略性的人 都不可能來到霎哈嘉瑜伽
So all such people were thrown out.
因此 所有這類人都被甩出去
Once they were thrown out they were showing their teeth, I should say.
我得說 一旦被甩出去 他們便開始發怒
They didn't like it that they were thrown out.
他們不喜歡自己被甩出去
But they understand now, some of them, that “we have made mistakes.”
但現在他們理解了 有些人會明白 我們犯了錯
So first thing is that you must develop your sense of chastity,
因此第一件事就是你要發展你的貞潔
respect it and enjoy it.
尊重它並享受它
That happened because of your Mooladhara being awakened.
這一切會發生是因為你的根輪被喚醒了
That's the first chakra on the left side, where you have Shri Ganesha.
那是左脈上的第一個輪穴 這裡駐守著錫呂 格涅沙
But on the right side also we have deities.
但是在右脈我們也有一些神祇
On every chakra we have deities to compensate,
每個輪穴都有一些神祇來平衡互補
but Shri Ganesha is in the center.
但錫呂 格涅沙處在中脈
And that's how we were blessed by His powerful purity,
因此我們獲得祂強大的祝福 而變得純潔
and we started understanding the beauty of purity,
我們開始理解純潔的美麗
the power of purity.
純潔的力量
That's how our right side we finished off.
這就是為什麼在右脈上啟動會完蛋
Right side was for fighting, for killing, anger.
右脈帶來戰爭 殺戮 憤怒
There was no peace for these people.
這些人沒有平安
The only thing they knew how to dominate others, and to be intolerable.
他們只知道一件事就是操控他人 沒有耐心
So then they rose to a higher, to higher level of Swadisthan.
接著他們升至更高的位置 腹輪
In Swadisthana they rose,
在腹輪 他們提升那些有創造力的人的侵略性 從而創造出一些東西
Even now we have many.
即使在現時還有很多這種東西
They create all kinds of nonsense, create all sorts of grotesque,
他們創造出各種廢物 創造各種怪誕的物品
also very, very, I should say, dirty things to make a name.
以及一些非常非常 我應說 非常骯髒的事物來博取名聲
So this is the another thing we got it in Swadisthana,
因此 這是我們在腹輪處 得到的其它東西
people who wanted to have a name, a position –
人們想要獲得的名譽和地位
that came from right Swadisthana.
那來自右腹輪
Then the third chakra that was there was the Nabhi Chakra.
然後那裡的第三個輪穴是臍輪
On the Nabhi Chakra they went all out to make money,
在臍輪我們全都出去賺錢
not Lakshmi but money, money by any means,
沒有拉希什米 只有金錢 通過各種手段賺錢
and they cheated the whole world.
他們欺騙全世界
With this money that they got, they did all kinds of bad things.
他們用賺來的錢 做各種各樣的壞事
Either they cheated or they were aggressive.
他們欺詐 或者侵略
Cheating was very much in the left-side countries like India,
欺詐在一些偏左脈的國家非常嚴重 比如印度
and aggressiveness in the right-side countries.
而侵略則出現在那些傾向右脈的國家
In the center, what quality we have at the Swadisthana is the creativeness:
在腹輪中部 我們所得到的特質是創造力
creative of art, which is very beautiful,
藝術創造 非常美
which is very deep, which is absolutely spiritual.
很深入 那是絕對充滿靈性的
That vanished, and people started showing
這些都消失了 人們開始展示 甚至是滿身骯髒劣習的降世神祇
All kinds of filth came in with that progress.
在那種進展中產出了各種污穢
Then, as I told you, there's Nabhi.
然後 正如我所說 我們有臍輪
In Nabhi people got after money.
在臍輪人們追逐金錢
Left-sided people were making money,
偏向左脈的人在賺錢
right-sided were aggressive with their money.
偏右脈的人在用錢侵略
If they were earning they thought they’re on top of the world.
如果他們能賺錢 他們便認為 自己站到了世界之巔
If they had money they thought, “Nobody is better than us.”
如果他們有錢 他們便會想 沒人比我們好
All this finished them off, it's finishing.
所有這一切使他們完蛋 完結了
It will come to that point where they will realize
最終會到達一個點 他們會意識到
that money is not for destroying but for construction:
金錢不是用來毀滅的 是用來建設的
constructing of the country, constructing of the human beings together
建設國家 將人類聯結到一起
to bring peace and love among them,
並在他們中間帶來平安和愛
for helping, for doing all kinds of good things.
金錢是用來幫助他人的 是用來做所有好事的
Then the same right-sided people went to the chakra of the Mother,
然後 同樣右脈的人來到了 代表母親的輪穴
dominate everyone, and could not sacrifice anything for the children.
操控每個人 無法為孩子做出任何犧牲
We have had enough of these women
這樣的女性已經夠多了
who are aggressive with their husbands, are aggressive with their children.
她們對丈夫和孩子咄咄逼人
And even the motherhood among men is dead and finished.
甚至連男人之中的母性 也已終結和完蛋
All that kind of lot when I came on this Earth I saw,
當我降生在地球上
and I was shocked – what sort of human beings are those?
我感到震驚 這都是些什麼人啊
What am I going to do with them?
我該拿他們怎麼辦
How will I awaken their kundalini?
我該怎麼喚醒他們的昆達利尼
At the Nabhi Chakra only they were lost,
在臍輪他們只是迷失了
but now it is the Mother's chakra.
但是現在輪到了代表母親的輪穴
They had no fatherhood, no motherhood, they drove out their children –
他們沒有父性 沒有母性 他們對孩子揠苗助長
very selfish, self-centered, dominating parents.
非常自私 自我中心 好宰製的父母
This was the Heart Chakra.
這就是在心輪所發生的事
Then came the collective chakra, what we call as the Vishuddhi.
然後 來到了集體意識的輪穴 我們稱之為喉輪
At the Vishuddhi Chakra they wanted to occupy the whole world.
在喉輪 他們想要佔領整個世界
They wanted to occupy the whole world as their own to become emperors,
他們想將整個世界占為己有 自己稱王
and they formed empires and misbehaved to such an extent
他們建造帝國 他們胡作非為
that it's not humanly possible to behave like that.
甚至已經達到了 非人類所能企及的地步
They really were rakshasas, I should say,
他們真的是羅刹魔
and those rakshas qualities are still there.
我要說 那些羅刹的特質還在那裡
In their behavior, in everything you can see how they behave
在他們的行為舉止中 在每件事中 你可以看到他們如何對人行事
towards people, treating them like that,
那樣地對待他們
creating people who are against spirituality,
他們制造反靈性和好侵略的人民
Well, these became like a two-sided world
然後這世界變成了雙面世界
where there are people who are aggressive,
即有充滿侵略的人
and the people who are tortured.
也有被折磨的人
This two-sided world exists even now, but is much less.
即使是現在 這個雙面世界 還繼續存在 只不過比以前少得多
Thanks to the collective understanding
感謝人們對集體性的理解
there are many good institution that were established
建立了許多很好的機構
but they are not working out, they are not so successful,
但是這些機構卻未能達成目標 他們並不算成功
because the men at the head of it are controlling, but controlling what?
因為這些機構的首領正在操控 但是控制什麼呢
Not themselves – controlling others,
不是控制他們自己 而是控制別人
and all their behavior has spoilt all the work of this chakra.
所有他們的這些行為都毀壞了 這個輪穴的運作
Collectively you have, if you see around now today
如今 如果你環顧四周
everywhere there’s war going on, fights going on, killing going on,
會看到在整體層面上到處都有戰爭 在進行 戰鬥在進行 殺戮在進行
destruction going on. How is it?
毀滅在進行 怎麼會這樣
There are so many spiritual people here now on this world.
現在這個世界有如此多 充滿靈性的人
So the reason is, the spiritual people have become very quiet,
所以 原因就是 這些有靈性的人變得非常安靜
very much enjoying their spiritual life,
非常享受他們的靈性生活
have become very quiet and very peaceful people.
變成了非常溫順和平安的人
But that doesn't bring peace.
但這樣並不能帶來和平
You have to be dynamic and you have to bring peace in the world,
你必須行動起來 你要為這個世界帶來和平
you have to do something about it.
你必須為此做點什麼
We are very much satisfied with our progress,
我們對自己的進化非常滿意
but we are not bothered as to see what is the progress others have done,
但是我們並沒有 花心思來看看其他人的進展如何
how far they have gone, where can we meet them,
他們已經走了多遠 我們會在哪裡與他們相遇
what can we change them.
我們可以改變些什麼
At My level I can change many things,
在我的層次 我可以改變許多事
but at your level how many people have you changed?
但是 在你的層次 你改變了多少人呢
What have you done? That has to be said.
你做過什麼呢 我們要看到這一切發生
Still you live with your ego, on the Agnya,
在額輪中 你仍然帶著你的自我
and you are very happy with your peace,
你對自己的平安感覺非常開心
with everything you have got through Sahaja Yoga.
對於在霎哈嘉瑜伽所獲得的一切 非常愉悅
This is the biggest calamity that the world is facing today,
這正是今天這個世界所面臨的 最大的災難
that those who are all so spiritual, those who have achieved great heights
那些充滿靈性 那些達至非凡靈性高度的人
are least bothered as to what good has to be done.
卻最不願關心要做點什麼有益的事情
What they are doing is to enjoy their own spirituality,
他們所做的就是享受他們的靈性
come to the puja, have more and more of it.
來參加普祭 越來越有靈性
But they have done no collective work to change people.
但他們並未集體性地開展工作 來改變別人
Some of them are working, one or two,
他們有些人是在工作 總共一兩個
but the rest of them are having a good time
但其餘那些人正以這樣一種方式 享受著自己的美好時光
that people accept them as great souls, good people, that's all.
就是人們認同他們是偉大的靈 是好人 這就是全部
I would like you to now introspect
現在我想要你們去內省
and find out how much collective work you have done,
看看你到底集體性地 開展了多少工作
how many people you have got – like that.
你轉化了多少人 就像這樣
With whom are you talking?
你和誰交談了
How many people have you told about Sahaja Yoga?
你對多少人提及霎哈嘉瑜伽
Only so many are there.
就這麼點人而已
Christ had only twelve disciples; they were much more dynamic than you are.
基督只有十二個門徒 他們卻比你們有行動力得多
So now you should take to the right side.
所以 現在你們要走向右脈
And when you take to the right side we'll create dynamic people,
當你們走向右脈 我們會創造有行動力的人
not just some useless, patient, very quiet, peaceful people.
而不只是一些無用的 能忍的 非常安靜 平和的人
This was not the aim of Sahaja Yoga.
那不是霎哈嘉瑜伽的目的
The aim of Sahaja Yoga is to change, change so many.
霎哈嘉瑜伽的目的是改變 改變如此多的人
And those who are doing that, all My blessings are with them.
那些這樣做的人 我所有的祝福將會伴隨著他
But those who are just keeping to themselves, it is not a very good thing.
但那些只是自己享用的人 這樣做並不太好
In your country how many people have got to Sahaja Yoga?
在你的國家有多少人 接觸過霎哈嘉瑜伽
Just find out. With how many people you have worked it out?
去找找看 你幫助多少人成就了它
So yours is not a complete yoga, yours is a partial yoga of the left side,
所以 你的霎哈嘉 並不是一個完全的瑜伽
where you are very loving, you are very kind, very this thing.
在這裡你可愛又和藹 只是這樣
I am not saying that you should become aggressive in any way.
無論如何 我並不是說 你要變得咄咄逼人
But even I have seen people want to be leaders, they want to be something great;
儘管我看到人們想成為領袖 他們想成為偉大的人
but how many people have they given realization?
但是 他們又給予了多少人自覺呢
How many people have they talked about Sahaja Yoga?
他們向多少人談論過霎哈嘉瑜伽
I have said even in the aeroplane also you go,
我說過 甚至在飛機上你也可以去做
you walk in the street, anywhere people talk about Sahaja Yoga.
走在街道上 去到任何地方 和人們談論霎哈嘉瑜伽
But here we are using Sahaja Yoga for our greatness,
但是在這裡我們使用霎哈嘉瑜伽 令自己變得偉大
for our understanding of ourselves.
用於瞭解我們自己
This is not why Sahaja Yoga has been brought to you.
這不是將霎哈嘉給予你的目的
It has been brought to you for giving realizations to many people.
把霎哈嘉瑜伽給你是為了 讓你去給予許多人自覺
I request all the younger people, younger generation
我請求所有的年青人 年輕一代
You’d better go ahead and talk to people about Sahaja Yog,
你最好走向前 和人們談論霎哈嘉瑜伽
and spread the Sahaja Yoga.
傳播霎哈嘉瑜伽
They are more interested in running schools, in looking after the destitute,
他們卻對於運營學校 照料貧困人群更有興趣
doing this, - doing that – that's not your job.
做這個 做那個 那不是你們的工作
Your job is to create more Sahaja yogis, more Sahaja yoginis.
你們的工作是創造更多的 霎哈嘉瑜伽士
But that is not there, what I find is it's not there.
但那並沒有發生 我所看到的是那沒有發生
The right side is missing. You should come to the right side.
右脈是缺失的 你應當來到右脈
Go all ahead. Nothing will happen to you. Nobody can kill you,
全都走向前 不會有什麼事發生在你身上 沒有人能殺害你
nobody can disturb you, nobody can arrest you, take it from Me.
沒有人會妨礙你 沒有人能逮捕你 相信我說的
You have powers but if you don't use them, you are like this.
你擁有力量 但如果你不用它 你就會像這樣
That is why we have come to the stagnated point
這正是為何我們停滯不前
that we should know we have to use our right side.
我們應當知道我們要使用右脈
Right side is very important.
右脈非常重要
Next time I'll tell you about right side, what right-sided things you have.
下次我會和你們談談右脈 你們在右脈上擁有什麼
Now you cannot become left-sided whatever you may try;
現在 你要嘗試各種方法讓自己 不能變得偏向左脈
so you use your right side in the right direction
因此 以恰當的理解 朝著正確的方向來運用你們的右脈吧
We have had also Hitlers among Sahaja yogis.
我們在霎哈嘉瑜伽中也 已經出現了希特勒
But now the time has come for you
但現在是時候了
to do something more than what the saints have done before,
你們要多做些事 比以前的聖人所做還要更多
to work it out that way; not to keep to yourself
用那樣的方式來成就它 不要把它留給自己
that you have a family, you have very nice children,
你擁有家庭 有非常可愛的孩子
having, enjoying, all that – that's not the Sahaja Yoga for.
擁有 享受 所有那些 那不是霎哈嘉瑜伽
Sahaja Yoga is for transforming the whole world.
霎哈嘉瑜伽是為了轉化全世界
You have to think about it: what are you doing, where are you,
你必須思考 你在做什麼 你在哪裡
and what have you achieved out of Sahaja Yoga?
你通過霎哈嘉成就了什麼
Then we come to the Agnya.
然後我們來到額輪
In Agnya what has happened is Sahaja yogis are become, they have,
在額輪所發生的是 霎哈嘉瑜伽士正在變得
they can bear anything, they can suffer anything – that's not we want.
已經變得可以容忍任何事 他們可以忍受任何事
What we want, to remove the sufferings of others,
我們所要的是去除他人的苦難
remove the aggression of others.
去除他人的侵略性
So we don't, that kind of organization we don't have,
的確 我們並沒有 我們沒有那種組織
that kind of understanding we don’t have.
我們沒有那種理解
And if that works out, you will be different people.
如果這一切可以成就 你們會變成不同的人
So we have become like saints, you see, sitting in their hermit halls,
因此 我們變得像聖人一樣 你瞧 坐在自己的隱居室裡
something like that, not more than that.
不幹任何其它事情
So better try to do something positive, without aggression.
所以 最好是不帶侵略性地 嘗試著去做一些積極的事
I know some of you are still very aggressive, are show-offs, I know that.
我知道 你們有些人 仍然非常好侵略 愛炫耀
But if you get into the mood of working out collectively,
但如果你進入某種集體成就的氛圍中
then you will realize what mistakes you have,
那麼 你會意識到 你犯了什麼錯
still what is lacking in your personality – that is very important.
你的性格裡還缺乏什麼 那非常重要
At Agnya Chakra many Sahaja yogis falter,
在額輪 有許多霎哈嘉瑜伽士 畏畏縮縮
I don't know what happens to them.
我不知道他們怎麼了
At Agnya I have told that you must forgive.
在額輪我告訴過你們 必須原諒
But that doesn't mean that you allow people to do wrong things.
但那並不意味著允許人們 做錯誤的事
Because you want to forgive it's very easy not to fight,
因為你想要原諒 如果不去戰鬥 不說什麼話 只是旁觀 只是原諒 那會非常容易
You have to face it.
你必須面對它
If you cannot face it then you are useless, just like any other people.
如果你不能面對它 那麼你是無用的 就像任何其他人一樣
What's the use of you people getting your realization?
你們這些人得到自覺又有什麼用呢
So now we have to understand that it's not only that we have vibrations,
所以現在我們必須瞭解 不僅僅是我們擁有了能量
that you can cure some people is the last word – no.
最好不過就是你還可以治癒人 不是這樣
You have to spread it, you have to go in the public,
你必須去傳播它 你必須走向公眾
you have to be collective on this point
在這一點上你要變得合群
and you have to spread Sahaja Yoga.
你必須傳播霎哈嘉瑜伽
With so many Sahaja yogis all over the world we have not progressed much.
全世界有如此多的霎哈嘉瑜伽士 我們卻並未有太大進展
So now it is you have to plan what you want to do,
因此 現在 你自己必須計畫 你要做什麼
how you want to do it, and how you want to spread Sahaja Yoga.
你要怎樣去做它 你要怎樣傳播霎哈嘉瑜伽
It's very important.
這是非常重要的
Because you people are good at, say, talking about Sahaja Yoga,
因為你們這些人擅于談論霎哈嘉
singing about Sahaja Yoga; all these things are useless unless and until
擅于歌唱霎哈嘉瑜伽 所有這些事都沒有用
you have concrete proof of getting many more people in Sahaja Yoga.
除非你能實實在在地證明帶了 更多人來到霎哈嘉瑜伽
In a small country like Turkey
在像土耳其這樣的小國家
we have 25000 Sahaja yogis, what do you say?
我們有25000位霎哈嘉瑜伽士 你能說什麼呢
They are all Muslims, twenty-five thousands Muslim becoming Sahaja yogis,
他們全都是穆斯林 25000名穆斯林 變成了霎哈嘉瑜伽士
while you find that number is very small in any other country.
而你會發現在任何其他國家 這個數字卻非常少
They are not very rich, but they care for their Self-realization
他們並不很富裕 但他們關心他們的自覺
and for toward giving Self-realizations to others.
他們關心給予其他人自覺
It's very surprising how it has worked out, how it has spread.
非常令人吃驚的是 霎哈嘉瑜伽在那裡是如何成就的 是如何傳播的
So instead of thinking of your problems, of your enemies, of your powers,
因此 不要再思考你的問題 你的敵人 你的力量了
think of giving power to others
而是想想如何把力量給予其他人
and making them Sahaja Yoga – it's very important.
如何把他們變成霎哈嘉瑜伽士 這非常重要
If you are in Sahasrara then you have all the powers.
如果你在頂輪 那麼你會擁有所有的力量
In Sahasrara if you do not spread Sahaja Yoga,
在頂輪 如果你不傳播霎哈嘉瑜伽
what's the use of getting realization?
得到自覺又有什麼用呢
Just for yourself – it's being very selfish.
只是為了你自己 那是非常自私的
So I would say that instead of spreading your own glory, your own name,
所以我要說 請不要傳播你自己的榮耀 你自己的名聲
please try to get more people to Sahaja Yoga.
而是努力帶更多人來到霎哈嘉瑜伽
Go into a very dynamic force.
充滿活力地行動起來
So many people have complained to Me
好多人向我抱怨
that Sahaja yogis are nothing but dead people.
霎哈嘉瑜伽士只不過是一些死氣沉沉的人
Is that what you are?
你們是那樣的嗎
Only single person like Me has done so much work, so why not you people?
只有像我這樣的一個人做了這麼多工作
In your country have you worked it out all over?
在你的整個國家 你成就出來了嗎
Just think about it.
去想想吧
And that's why, unless and until you don't do it you are not sampurna,
那就是為什麼 除非你這麼做 否則你不是sampurna你並不完整
and the Adi Shakti's powers you have not understood in its full form.
你並沒有理解太初之母 這一完整形象的力量
That's why I'm telling you today it's a very important day
那就是今天我為什麼要告訴你們
But you should know that Adi Shakti has to be a complete form.
但你們應當知道 太初之母必須是一個整全的形象
It cannot be only half left-sided – no.
不能是僅僅左脈半邊 不是那樣
If that doesn't work out, then what's the use?
如果不能成就 又有什麼用呢
It's like any other getting any other realization – that's not so important.
就好像任何其他人 意識到了任何其它事情 那並不怎麼重要
Not only that you should spread,
你們不僅僅要去傳播霎哈嘉
but also you should make them, and realize it.
還要讓瑜伽士們意識到這一點
All My blessings, all My love, all My powers I give you;
我將我所有的祝福 所有的愛 所有的力量給予你們
but try to understand. All right?
但試著去理解這一切吧 好嗎
Thank you very much.
非常感謝